flykingfisher.com 2011-12-04

# Kingfisher Airlines - Airline Privacy Policy

### **Privacy Policy Statement**

Maintaining the privacy of your information is a high priority to Kingfisher Airlines Limited (“Kingfisher Airlines”). This internet privacy Policy (the “Policy”) summarizes what personally identifiable information we may collect from you, and how we might use this information. The Policy describes how we protect your privacy when we collect personal information on flykingfisher.com (“Web site”). As used in the Policy, the term “Personal Information” means information that identifies you personally, alone or in combination with other information available to Kingfisher Airlines. By continuing to use the Web site and by providing personal information, you consent to the Policy. You should read the entire Policy carefully and review the Policy periodically to remain aware of the current policies and practices. 

**Your personal information**

When you use services provided on our Web site, you will be asked to provide certain personal identifiable information such as your name, address, telephone numbers, fax numbers, email address and/or debit / credit card details including billing address, passport number and nationality.   
When you enroll in our King Club Programme , you are asked to provide certain  personal information such as your name, contact details, date of birth and business details (company name, job title, address and contact information). If you are already a King Club Member, you may provide information to us that enables us to create a traveler profile for you, which is optional. In creating a guest profile you also share information about your travel preferences, hobbies and business details.  
Kingfisher Airlines occasionally sponsors promotions and contests to give visitors and members the opportunity to win various prizes. We may combine personal identifiable information from promotions and contests with personal information collected through cookies and other means as stated herein below:  
Cookies - A “cookie” is a small bit of text used by a browser to store information. When you visit a Web site that uses cookies, the Web server will request permission to pass a cookie to your browser. If accepted, it will occupy only a few bytes on your hard drive and can improve your Web surfing experience. Kingfisher Airlines uses cookies to track customer visits through our Web site. This information enables us to save you time when returning to the Web site by saving your password so you do not have to re-enter it each time you visit. Cookies cannot profile your system or collect information from your hard drive. And although you may receive cookies from many different Web sites, each cookie can only be read by the Web server that originally issued it. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but you can set your browsers to refuse cookies.  
We may aggregate personal information and remove any identifying elements in order to analyze patterns and improve our marketing and promotional efforts, to analyze Web site use, to improve our content and product offerings, and to customize our Web site’s content, layout and services.  
We gather certain usage information like the number and frequency of visitors to this Web site. This information may include which URL you just came from, which URL you next go to, what browser you are using, and your IP address. We only use such data in the aggregate. This collective data helps us to determine how much our customers use parts of the Web site, and do internal research on our users’ demographics, interests, and behaviour to better understand and serve you. 

**Use of your personal information**

Personal Information you provide or that is obtained by us will be used by us to enable us to review, develop and improve the services which we offer and provide you and other customers (via mail, email telephone or otherwise) with information about new products and services and special offers we think you will find valuable. We may also inform you about new products and services and special offers of selected third parties.  
We also use Personal Information in the following ways: 

  1. process your flight details, sending you your itinerary, or contacting you if there is a problem with your reservation;
  2. to register you with our Web site and administer our Web site services where you have so registered. You can unsubscribe from these services at any time at the bottom of the e-mails sent to you.
  3. to administer any contest or other promotional offer you may enter and notify winners;
  4. to answer any queries which you may send to us by email;
  5. in order to conduct customer satisfaction surveys;
  6. to meet our legal compliance obligations;
  7. for crime prevention and detection; and
  8. for marketing purposes, as set out in detail below.  

We need to know the names of all passengers travelling. If you are booking a flight on behalf of someone else, you must obtain their consent to use their personal information. We proceed on the basis that you have obtained this consent. 

**Disclosure of your personal information**

Kingfisher Airlines may share your personal identifiable information to third party service providers and processors with access to your personal information. These services providers may include: credit card verification providers, our data warehouse and customer relationship management centre, marketing organizations, who may provide support marketing and promotional communications; internet service providers who administer our web page and provide internet services and host our facilities; chauffeurs, car services agencies, and consumer research companies that assist Kingfisher Airlines with understanding consumer interests by conducting surveys. Kingfisher Airlines only shares your personal information to the extent required for the performance of such services.   
Kingfisher Airlines may share your personal identifiable information with our partners, affiliates and also selected third party providers of flight related benefits and services, who in turn may contact you directly using your personal identifiable information in order to provide you with details of additional benefits and services which may be of interest to you. Where we do so, we require those partners, affiliates and/or third parties to have appropriate measures in place to protect your personal identifiable information and comply with all applicable legislation and rules  
Kingfisher Airlines may also disclose your personal identifiable information as permitted or required by law. For example, Kingfisher Airlines will disclose personal information to those governmental bodies who have authority to obtain it, in order to comply with a warrant or subpoena issued by a court of competent jurisdiction, and to comply with record production requirements.  
In the event of a sale of all or substantially all of the assets of Kingfisher Airlines, Kingfisher Airlines may transfer personal information in its control to a third party purchaser that agrees to use personal information for the same reasons identified in this Privacy Policy. 

  1. to anyone to whom we transfer or may transfer our rights and duties under our agreement with you;
  2. to customs and/or immigration departments or other regulatory authorities in your country of departure and/or destination in order to comply with the law in those countries;
  3. if we have a duty to do so or if the law allows us to do so;
  4. to our employees and agents to do any of the above on our behalf, now or in the future.

If you choose not to provide certain personal information we request, you will still be able to visit our Web site but you may be unable to access certain options or services. 

We make no warranty, express, implied or otherwise as to the privacy and data security practices of the third parties, our partners and affiliates.We will however make reasonable endeavours to ensure that such third parties, partners and affiliates exercise reasonable care in handling your personal identifiable information in accordance with industry norms and standards. 

**Consent**

By choosing to provide Kingfisher Airlines with your personal information you are consenting to its use in accordance with the principles outlined in the Policy and as outlined at the time you are asked to provide any personal information. Kingfisher Airlines may contact you by phone or email in order to provide you with updates pertaining to its services as well as information about additional offers, products or events that Kingfisher Airlines believes may be of interest to you. You can choose to unsubscribe to these updates or from having your personal information used for market research purposes. 

**Withdrawing your consent**

All e-mails Kingfisher Airlines sends to you will provide you with an option to withdraw your consent. If you no longer wish to receive promotional materials, you may opt-out of receiving these communications, by reply to unsubscribe in the e-mail footer, this will remove you from Kingfisher Airlines’ mail lists. To unsubscribe from King Club communication, you will have to go to kingclub.flykingfisher.com and log into your account. You will always be notified when information is being collected by any outside parties. We do this to enable you to make an informed choice as to whether we should proceed with the services that require an outside party, or not.  
Please note that if you do not consent to Kingfisher Airlines’s use and disclosure of your personal information, this may affect our ability to provide you with particular products and services. 

**Security**

We will take appropriate steps to protect the personal information you share with us. We have implemented technology and security features to safeguard the privacy of your personal information. 

**Links**

Our Web site may contain links to other Web sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of Web sites not operated by us or an entity in the "Kingfisher Airlines Group". We encourage you to read the Privacy Policy of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This Policy applies solely to information collected by our Web site. 

**Correction / updating of personal information**

If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, we will provide a way to correct, update or remove your personal information provided to us. 

**Access to your personal information**

You have the right to see personal information we keep about you. We will endeavour to provide the information you require within a reasonable time. There may be a small monetary charge for some requests, depending on the information requested. If you are concerned that any of the information we hold on you is incorrect please contact us. 

**Transfer of your personal information**

Some parties that process or store personal information may be located in jurisdictions outside your country of residence. Therefore, your information may be processed and stored in these jurisdictions and, as a result, foreign governments, courts, or law enforcement or regulatory agencies may be able to obtain disclosure of your information through the laws in these countries. 

**Notification of changes**

We reserve the right to update or modify the Policy, at any time and without prior notice, by posting the revised version of the Policy on our Web site. If we decide to change and/or modify our Policy, we will post those changes on our Web site so you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify you by way of an email. If you so wish, you may withdraw your consent to such use subject to and in accordance with the terms of our Policy.  
Kingfisher Airlines has implemented safeguards to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure and improper use of personal identifiable information and to maintain data security in a way that is consistent with the terms of this Policy and that it is never used except to fulfill services to Kingfisher Airlines. These security measures include secure socket layer (SSL) that encrypts data that you transmit to the site. Although we take reasonable steps to prevent unauthorized access we cannot be held responsible for the acts of those who gain unauthorized access, we make no warranty, express, implied or otherwise, that we will prevent unauthorized access to your personal identifiable information.
